

VISHAL SUBHASH BIDAWATKA

Lalbhai Dalpatbhai College of Engineering, Ahmedabad - 380015

Email: **DOB**: 15th Feb, 1997

vishalbidawatka0@gmail.com vishal.bidawatka@dynamichub.in

Address: A-74, Parshwanath Towers, Gurukul, Ahmedabad - 380052

ABOUT ME

www.linkedin.com/in/vishal-bidawatka-387073109/

I am pursuing engineering in Information Technology from L.D. College of Engineering. I want to explore more aspects of deep learning, want to represent something solid on paper in this vast field of uncertainty, want to build machines that act rationally like brain regarding any problem. I have strong basics of data structures, algorithms, search problems, computer vision, cloud technology and machine learning. I am currently exploring various branches of Artificial Intelligence. To test my knowledge about these topics I have completed many projects including real-life statement problems and internships described below. I also have proficiency in Graphic Designing (Coral Draw) and served many clients (Writopedia, THC Labs etc.).

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE / INTERNSHIPS

Meditab (Artificial Intelligence)

Feb 2017 to Present

Meditab is a leading software solutions company that has been continuously changing the landscape of healthcare delivery through forward thinking. I have been assigned two projects which are mentioned in project section.

Appointed by: Param Rajpura

Vox Populi Magazine (Senior Designer)

March 2016 to Present

This is the college's annual magazine delivered to more than 6000 students and faculty members. As a senior designer, my work is to effectively produce better designs which suits the article and deliver vibrant output.

Appointed by: Editor and committee

Dynamic Hub (Founder and CEO)

Oct 2016 to June 2017 (8 months)

This is the company founded by me. Here we offer the IT services as website development, Application Development, SEO, content writing, etc. I have worked very hard for the progress of the company by serving as Executive head and Developer

Writopedia (Data Analytics)

July 2016 - Aug 2016 (2 months)

Writopedia is an international content writing company which offers many types writing services. I was hired by them as an intern to develop and manage their data and find pattern in the statistics. Also, I was the leading graphic designer for the firm for printing media.

Under: Mr. Hardeep Pathak & Mr. Ashwin Ramesh

PROJECTS

www.github.com/vishalbidawatka

Pill Recognizer (Meditab)

Core Concept: Computer Vision

The aim of this system was to verify that the pills that are dropped by our robot with respect to given prescription are correct or not with respect to numer of pills and the pill id. It used opency methods to threshold the image obtained from

two angles and the main achievement was to separate the contour of the pills which fall and accumulate together.

Guide: Mr. Param Rajpura (Team Lead at Meditab Al Department)

Car Navigation (Meditab)

Core Concept: Reinforcement Learning

We have a track on which robot cars move and collect pills form the central system and bring them to user end while moving on the track. We implemented reinforcement learning to train cars to avoid collision and find optimal path without forming any deadlock. We built a basic simulator to test the changes as hardware testing can be more dangerous and costlier and later implemented the same in cars. We used the search algorithms, reinforcement reward policy and we look ahead to advance our system by using deep reinforcement learning.

Guide: Mr. Param Rajpura (Team Lead at Meditab Al Department)

Automatic Examination System

Core Concept: Machine Learning

Our system aims to remove Tutor dependencies during the time of self-examination. We aim to generate a system which can generate questions on given topic and analyze the answer given to each question on the basis of the relevance to the question. We used NLTK library along with sequence to sequence neural network which acts as encoder decoder scheme. We generated MCQs, Blanks, descriptive type of questions from given text or image.

Guide: Prof. Dr. Thaker Chirag (L.D. College of Engineering)

AWS Image Compressor

Concept: AWS S3 Bucket + Lamda Function

Using lamda function and its automatic invocation by S3 bucket I created an image compressor which when an image is uploaded to one bucket, its compressed thumbnail gets generated in another bucket.

Self-made

Future Frame Analysis

Core Concept: Machine Learning

This system aims to predict few future video frames on the basis of the video itself. Our aim is to predict the action in the video after the end of the video, by the use of machine learning and object sequence analysis.

Guide: Mr. Rebanta Kanungoe & Mr. Siddhant Agarwal (INTEL Representatives)

Drowsy Driver

Core Concept: Machine Learning

This project uses opency along side some pixel calculation. Whenever the eyes of driver remains closed for more than certain second, it detects the situation and wakes him up with an alarm. Still lot has to be done for correctly determining yawning. We used haar cascade and detected eyes and then calculated the ratio of white and black pixels. We are moving ahead in the direction of using CNN for optimal results.

Self-made

Awards and Achievements

- 2nd Rank at Department
- As a part of Vox-Populi Club (Socio-Cultural Club) in my college, I managed, coordinated, volunteered for and campaigned for many technical and non-technical events such as Xitij, Lakshya, Udaan and Orientation in my college.
- Senior Designer of the college yearly magazine which is distributed among 6000 students.
- Scored 89 Percentile in NPAT exam conducted by IIT Madras
- Served 10+ clients as a Founder of the Start-up named Dynamic Hub (Dynamichub.in) [Closed after break-even].
- Participated in ChessCode event at Charotar University.
- Provided tutoring to underprivileged children, helped in traffic management with police, participated in RUN for UNITY marathon as a junior member of NGO Yuva Unstoppable.
- Keen to explore AWS Cloud (ec2, rds, s3, rekoginiton, elastic beanstalk and more) alongside using its computational power to train machine learning models.
- Participated in International Conference On Geothermal Energy Exploration at PDPU.
- More than 100 tasks completed at HACKERRANK (https://www.hackerrank.com/vishal75).
- Successfully Designed and published YearBook (2016).
- Part of various teams involved in projects like Automatic Question answer generator, Object Detection & face recognition, Web automation and more.
- Actively involved in playing Volleyball (Front blocker, smasher)

EDUCATION

Degree	University/Institute	Year	CPI/Percentage
B.E. (IT)	L.D. College of Engineering, Ahmedabad, Gujarat Technological University	2018	9.08
HSC	Gujarat Law Society, Ahmedabad Gujarat Secondary and Higher Secondary Education Board	2014	83.4%
SSC	Gujarat Law Society, Ahmedabad. Gujarat Secondary and Higher Secondary Education Board	2012	91%

Skills

- Ÿ Good command over few core languages such as JAVA, Python.
- Ÿ Considerable knowledge about Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence and its tools/libraries like Keras, Tensorflow, Scikit Learn, Intel Colfax Clusters.
- Ÿ Intermediate level knowledge of cloud services with AWS and Google Cloud Platform.
- Ÿ Adaptive and Versatile engineer having more focus on problem-solving rather than language oriented approach.
- Ϋ́ Ability to work in a team as well as lead the team.

Personal

Languages Known English, Gujarati, Hindi

Marital Status Single

Nationality Indian

Contact Number +91-9408881872

Email Id vishal.bidawatka@dynamichub.com

vishalbidawatka0@gmail.com